Inventory of the Thomas Byrne Edsall papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Media--Notes, undated (Box-folder 123: 3)
- Clippings, 1972 October – 1987 March (Box-folder 123: 4-6)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1970 August - 1987 March 26 (Box 123)
- Various journals, 1982 Fall - 1987 March (Box 123)
- Clippings, 1970 June 29 – 1975 February 21 (Box 124)
- Clippings, 1970 June 29 – 1975 February 21 (Box 125)
- Household clippings-—Photo lab and restaurants in Washington, D.C., and guest list, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 126: 1)
- Tyson street-—Clippings, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 126: 2)
  House and ground information
- Lawrence J. Hogan, 1969-1975 (Box 126)
  Biographical information, itemized receipts for contributions, loans, letters, photocopies of articles, press release, and report
- Miscellany, 1968 (Box 126)
  Congressional report and notes
- New Republic, 1984 October 22 (Box-folder 127: 1)
- The New Politics of Inequality, 1984
  - Reviews and letters, 1984 (Box-folder 127: 2)
  - Reviews to Xerox, 1984 (Box-folder 127: 3-5)
  - Possible publication blurbs, 1983 (Box-folder 127: 6)
- William H. Frey, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 127: 7-8)
  Articles and research reports
- Reviews of The New Politics of Inequality, 1984 (Box 127)
- Photographs (Box 128)
  - 20 contact sheets, undated (Box-folder 128: 1)
  - Negatives, undated (Box-folder 128: 2-4)
  - Miscellaneous photography related papers, 1964-1966 (Box 128)
  - 68 unidentified prints, undated (Box-folder 129: 1-6)
  - 1 print depicting the Kemp family, undated
  - 1 print depicting Thomas Edsall and others at the going away party for Walter Robinson at Tom Oliphant's house?, 1990
  - 1 print depicting exterior of a house, 1995
- Provide, 1996 (Box-folder 130: 1)
- Psycho angelic Boston, 1994 (Box-folder 130: 2)
- Quotes, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 130: 3)
- Radio talk, undated (Box-folder 130: 4)
  Instruction sheet for "Talk of the Nation" guests
- Recovery movement, 1996 (Box-folder 130: 5)
- Rights, 1964-1994 (Box-folder 130: 6)
- Parenting rights, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 130: 7)
- Property rights, 1996 (Box-folder 130: 8)
- Revolution--Rights, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 130: 9)
- Letters from Byron E. Shafer to Thomas Edsall, 1995 (Box-folder 130: 10)
- Tailhook, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 130: 11)
  Articles, book outline for "American Men," chapter two of The Cultural and Social Revolutions, clippings, interview of John White on "This Week with David Brinkley," news release, and notes
- Tom Best--"What Went into Doing a Good Story on the Anti-NAFTA Forces,", 1993 (Box-folder 130: 12)
- The Cannon, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 130: 13)
  Article, book review, and clipping
- Timeline for books, 1970s-1990s (Box-folder 130: 14)
  List of bestsellers
- The Trends Journal, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 130: 15)
- Twentieth Century Fund, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 130: 16)
  Clipping and proposal
- Paul M. Sniderman, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 130: 17)
  Letters to Thomas Edsall from Paul Sniderman regarding the conference on race in American society and politics, 1990 March 23-24, and list of participants. Includes papers by Sniderman
- Social control, 1996 (Box-folder 130: 18)
- Socialism, undated (Box-folder 130: 19)
  Article
- South, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 130: 20)
  Clipping, graphs, and table showing racial voting patterns in southern senate elections and lists of black representatives per Congress
- Spiritual, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 130: 21)
- Nexus I, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 131: 1)
  Articles and papers by others, clippings, and draft notes by Thomas Edsall for "American Men" recorded on Miami tapes and in Washington Post articles
- Welfare, 1995 (Box-folder 131: 2)
  Reviews of books by Thomas Edsall
- Nexus II--Current, 1996 (Box-folder 131: 3)
  Notes about "American Men" and book outline
- Offers, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 131: 4)
  Brochure, letters, and list of fellows at the Institute of Politics
- Prospectus, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 131: 5)
  Outline for "American Men" by Thomas and Mary Edsall
- Bob Packwood, 1995 (Box-folder 131: 6)
  Article and clippings
- Paradigms, 1994 (Box-folder 131: 7)
- Patents, 1993 (Box-folder 131: 8)
  U.S. Department of Commerce June report update
- Phone numbers, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 131: 9)
  Includes notes
- John H. Pleck, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 131: 10)
- Prison, 1987-1996 (Box-folder 131: 11)
  Articles, clippings, and categorical grant progress report from the U.S. Department of Justice
- Prisoners' rights, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 131: 12)
  Articles, brochures, court papers, list of regional offices, and status reports
- Procreation--Men, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 131: 13)
- Book materials--Important (Box 132)
  - Folder 4 of 7, articles and reports 2, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 132: 1)
  - Folder 5 of 7, reports, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 132: 2)
  - Folder 6 of 7, Robert Hogan and Bruce Nelson, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 132: 3)
    Articles, draft chapters, and interviews
  - Folder 7 of 7, Abigail Trafford novels, 1998 (Box-folder 133: 1)
- Factual material from Post, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 133: 2)
- Kevin Macdonald, 1995? (Box-folder 133: 3)
- Montgomery Heart Foundation--Robert A. and Meg Friske Montgomery, 1997 (Box-folder 133: 4)
  Articles about heart disease, biographical note, information sheet, and letters to the editor and to Siebert
- Dick Morris, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 133: 5)
  Clippings and magazine
- Charles Moskos, 1997 (Box-folder 133: 6)
- Jeremy Nahum, 1984-1993 (Box-folder 133: 7)
  Article and related materials
- Eugene Narrett, 1995 (Box-folder 133: 8)
- Book materials--Important (Box 134)
  - Folder 1 of 7, correspondence, memoranda, and notes, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 134: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 7, magazines, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 134: 2)
  - Folder 3 of 7, articles and reports, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 134: 3)
- Men's studies, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 135: 1)
  Book review and clipping
- Men--War, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 135: 2)
- Men--Web, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 135: 3)
- Militia, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 135: 4)
- Military culture, 1997 (Box-folder 135: 5)
- Military pregnancy, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 135: 6)
- Military women, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 135: 7)
  Clippings and newsletters
- Million Man March, 1995 (Box-folder 135: 8)
- Alexander Mitscherlich, 1969? Society without the Father: A Contribution to Social Psychology--Translated from German by Eric Mosbacher (Box-folder 135: 9)
- John Locke, 1997 (Box-folder 136: 1)
  Clipping and miscellany
- Male bonding, 1996 (Box-folder 136: 2)
- Male coalition, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 136: 3)
- Male/Female
  - Dependence, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 4)
  - Difference, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 5)
- Masculine thinking, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 136: 6)
  Book review and notes
- Master plan, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 7)
- Timothy McVeigh, 1995 (Box-folder 136: 8)
- Men--E-mail, 1995 (Box-folder 136: 9)
- Memoirs--Thomas Edsall, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 136: 10)
  Clipping and notes
- Men--Extras
  - Altruism, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 136: 11)
  - E-mail, 1995 (Box-folder 136: 12)
  - Honor, undated (Box-folder 136: 13)
    Review of a book by James Bowman
  - Male artists, 1995 (Box-folder 136: 14)
  - Attitude, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 15)
  - Bad men, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 16)
  - Guys, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 17)
  - Lost men, 1991 (Box-folder 136: 18)
  - New men, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 136: 19)
  - Networking, 1996 (Box-folder 136: 20)
  - Providers, 1996 (Box-folder 136: 21)
  - Psychoanalytic view, undated (Box-folder 136: 22)
  - Steel, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 136: 23)
  - Style, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 24)
  - Support, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 136: 25)
  - Theory, 1993 (Box-folder 136: 26)
  - Unions, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 136: 27)
- Men--Extras II
  - Militias, 1996 (Box-folder 136: 28)
  - Father/Son, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 136: 29)
    Article, clipping, and press release
  - Feminists, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 136: 30)
  - Heroes, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 31)
  - Identity literature, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 32)
  - Infidelity, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 33)
  - Jobs, 1996 (Box-folder 136: 34)
  - Letters to the editor, 1995 (Box-folder 136: 35)
  - Men's groups, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 36)
  - Military, 1995 (Box-folder 136: 37)
  - Nexus, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 38)
  - Physical strength, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 136: 39)
  - Relationships, 1995 (Box-folder 136: 40)
    Review of a book
  - Science and technology, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 41)
  - Successful, 1994 (Box-folder 136: 42)
  - Men's movement, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 136: 43)
    Letter and information sheet from the Internet
  - Men's rights, 1995 (Box-folder 136: 44)
    Miscellany
- 2004 clips 1 (Box 137)
  - Folder 1 of 2, clippings, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 137: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 2, correspondence and magazines, 1990-1998 (Box-folder 137: 2)
- Ideology, 1990 (Box-folder 137: 3)
- Illegitimacy, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 137: 4)
  Brochure, clippings, and miscellany
- Kahlenberg?, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 137: 5)
  Mary Edsall's day lists, financial records relating to Compaq Presario and Toshiba computers, messages, notes, and miscellany
- World guide, 1996 (Box-folder 137: 6)
  Interview of James Hillman
- Seymour Martin Lipset, 1996 (Box-folder 137: 7)
- Male sexuality--Mailing, 1990-1999 (Box-folder 138: 1)
  Articles, clippings, and reports
- 2004 clips, 2003 (Box-folder 138: 2)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, and magazines
- Random information perhaps to be worked into book, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 139: 1)
- 2003 information to go into book, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 139: 2)
  Articles, lists, magazines, notes, and miscellany
- To be incorporated into book, 1992-2003 (Box-folder 140: 1)
  Articles, memoranda, and notes
- Women doing well, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 140: 2)
  Clippings and magazines
- Unlabeled, 1998 (Box-folder 141: 1)
- "Lyford" glass ceiling, 1976-1998 (Box-folder 141: 2)
  Articles and brochure
- To be incorporated into book (folder 5 of 5), 1997 (Box-folder 141: 3)
  Articles, brochure, and report
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), 1997 (Box-folder 142: 1)
- Election, 1994 (Box-folder 142: 2)
  Articles, U.S. News & World Report
- Miscellany (Box-folder 142: 3)
  - Two Majorities,", 1995
    Typescript chapters?
  - Article, International Journal of Public Opinion Research, 1991
  - Avner offer, 1994
    Includes a typescript draft of a chapter, undated, and an article co-authored with Sue Bowden, The Economic History Review, 1994
  - Correspondence between Thomas Edsall and Byron Shafer, 1994-1995, and itinerary of Thomas Edsall
  - Oxford University Gazette, 1995
    Special lecture list, Trinity Term
  - Tony Blair, 1994-1995
    Articles and list of stories
  - "The Cultural Revolution of 1994: Newt Gingrich, the Republican Party, and the Third Great Awakening," Oxford talk, Nuffield College, 1995 May 18
    Includes a letter from Byron Shafer, 1996
- Elites--Male, 1997 (Box-folder 142: 4)
  Article in Vanity Fair
- Jason Epstein, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 142: 5)
  Includes articles by Judith Miller, Thomas Edsall, and others; clippings; a copy of "American Men" with Mary Edsall as co-author; correspondence with Random House; and notes
- Futurism, 1995 (Box-folder 142: 6)
- Genetics, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 142: 7)
- John Gay, 1997 (Box-folder 142: 8)
- John Gay, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 143: 1)
  Manuscript and related materials
- Genetics, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 143: 2)
- George Gilder and Alvin and Heidi Toffler, 1980-1995 (Box-folder 143: 3)
  Article and book review
- Woman's Place in Man's Life Cycle," Carol Gilligan, 1978 (Box-folder 143: 4)
- "How to Be a Man," David D. Gilmore, Smithsonian Associates Program, 1991 July 17 (Box-folder 143: 5)
- Candice Gingrich, 1996 (Box-folder 143: 6)
- Newt Gingrich, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 143: 7)
  "Talking Heads: A Newt Gingrich Chrestomathy." Articles, clippings, comments, comprehensive report about his congressional career, interview, and speeches and writings
- Globalization, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 143: 8)
  Clippings and articles
- Steven Goldberg, 1996 (Box-folder 143: 9)
  Replies to "Patriarchy Debate"
- Jews in Germany: Under Prussian Rule, 1984
  Brochure for an exhibition organized by the Bildarchiv Preussischer Kulturbesitz, Berlin, in cooperation with the Leo Baeck Institute, New York
- Legal history, 60s – 70s, women's rights (Box 144)
  - Folder 3 of 4 (Box-folder 144: 1)
    - Feminist, 1991-1996
      Articles, clippings, and newsletter
    - Sexual harassment, 1993-1997
      Article, advertisement, clippings, and American Association of University Women (AAUW) press kit
    - Feminist, 1993-1996
      Articles, clippings, and report
  - Folder 4 of 4 (Box-folder 144: 2)
    - Feminism--Difference, 1992-1996
    - Feminism, 1984-1996
      Includes articles; clippings; women and gender studies courses, Columbia University, New York; letters from Margaret Morgan and Carl Schwartz to Thomas Edsall; and report
    - Women, 1993-1996
      Articles, clippings, and letters
    - Polygamy, 1996-1997
      Clippings and paper by Ted Bergstrom
    - Divorce, 1994-1997
    - Judith Lichtman, 1997
      Telephone interview
    - Narianne Glendon, 1997
- Economy, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 145: 1)
  Clipping, newsletter, and an issue of Dissent
- Thomas Edsall news, 1996 (Box-folder 145: 2)
- Thomas Edsall--"Homosexuality and Society,", undated (Box-folder 145: 3)
  Bibliography
- Thomas Edsall, undated (Box-folder 145: 4)
  Note to self
- Thomas Edsall--Publication, 1994 (Box-folder 145: 5)
  Article, "In Love with Limbaugh," New York Review of Books; clippings; and a memorandum to Thomas Edsall regarding Rush Limbaugh radio program
- Education, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 145: 6)
  Articles, clippings, press release, list of recommendations for reading, report, and statement
- Home schooling, 1996 (Box-folder 145: 7)
- Testing, 1994 (Box-folder 145: 8)
- Legal history, 60s – 70s, women's rights (folder 2 of 4), 1989-1997 (Box-folder 146: 1)
  Articles, book, and journal
- TBE AM ("American Men") prospect 2000 (Box 147)
  - Printed materials relating to Clinton-Gore administration, 1993-1999 (Box-folder 147: 1)
  - Articles and clippings by Thomas Edsall, 2000
- Legal history, 60s – 70s, women's rights (folder 1 of 4), 1993-1997 (Box-folder 147: 2)
  Interviews and comments on cultural counter-revolution articles
- Unsorted--11/98--Material in here for book must be sorted, (folder 3 of 3), 1993-1999 (Box-folder 148: 1)
  Correspondence, magazines, memoranda, and notes
- Pulled from bedroom stacks, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 148: 2)
  Chapter 2--Article, clippings, and magazines
- Unsorted--11/98--Material in here for book must be sorted (Box 149)
  - Folder 1 of 3, clippings, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 149: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 3, articles, 1987-1998 (Box-folder 149: 2)
- Immediate most important documents August 2003 (Box 150)
  - Folder 1 of 2, articles, clippings, correspondence, and memoranda, 2003 (Box-folder 150: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 2, magazines, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 150: 2)
- To be filed--Give to David A.
  - Folder 1 of 3, clippings, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 150: 3)
  - Folder 2 of 3, articles and magazines, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 151: 1)
  - Folder 3 of 3, articles and memoranda, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 151: 2)
- Current Docs, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 151: 3)
  Articles, clippings, and magazines
- First priority to go in unified one, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 151: 4)
  Articles, clippings, and memoranda
- Tom to read, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 152: 1)
- TBE "American Men" clips 2001 October 11 (Box 153)
  - Good-bad men, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 153: 1)
  - Feminization, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 153: 2)
  - Books and clippings, 2002-2003
- Tom to read, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 153: 3)
- "American Men" clips 2001 October 11, 1998-2003 (Box-folder 154: 1)
  Magazines
- Men, folder 1 of 2, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 155: 1)
  Memoranda, notes, and outlines
- Priority interviews, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 155: 2)
  Articles, clippings, and notes
- Downsize, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 155: 3)
- Unsorted clips (Box 156)
  - Folder 1 of 2, magazines, 1999 (Box-folder 156: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 2
    - Books on men/women, 1999 (Box-folder 156: 2)
    - Articles, book lists, clippings, and correspondence, 1999
- Men '04, 2004 (Box-folder 157: 1)
  Draft chapters of "American Men" by Thomas and Mary Edsall and "Borderlands: 'American Men' at the Extremes of the Social Order" by Thomas Edsall
- Men's (folder 2 of 2), 1995-1999 (Box-folder 157: 2)
- Core information regarding men (Box 158)
  - Books, 1998 (Box-folder 158: 1)
  - Kingsley Brown et al., 1998 (Box-folder 158: 2)
    Articles, book, correspondence, and notes
- Men--Drafts (Box 159)
  - Folder 1 of 2, chapter 1, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 159: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 2, chapters 1 and 2, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 159: 2)
    Drafts and selected interviews
- TBE "American Men" clips 2001 October 11 III (folder 3 of ?), 2000-2003 (Box-folder 160: 1)
- Core information regarding men, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 160: 2)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, magazines, and notes
- TBE "American Men" clips 2001 October 11 III, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 161: 1)
- Intelligent education, 1996 (Box-folder 162: 1)
- Interviews--Men, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 162: 2)
- Lawyers--Top men/money men in politics, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 162: 3)
- Left coalition--Culture wars, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 162: 4)
  Clippings and letter
- TBE "American Men" clips 2001 October 11 III (folder 2 of ?) (Box-folder 162: 5)
- Wayne, John, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 163: 1)
  Article by Dan Barden
- Webb, James, 1997 (Box-folder 163: 2)
- White underclass, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 163: 3)
- White men
  - Article, clippings, and magazine, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 163: 4)
  - Hegemony, 1994 (Box-folder 163: 5)
  - Root, Hilton, University of Pennsylvania--White male denied tenure, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 163: 6)
    Article, biographical note, course evaluations, and letter
- Wilson, James Q., 1993-1994 (Box-folder 163: 7)
  Clipping. Includes "Crisis and Challenge: Race and the New Urban Poverty," lecture by William J. Wilson, University of Chicago
- Women ascendance, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 163: 8)
- Women's achievements, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 163: 9-10)
  Clippings, guide and report
- Tiger, Lionel, 1996 (Box-folder 164: 1)
- Thomas Edsall, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 164: 2-3)
  - Female, 1996 (Box-folder 164: 4)
  - Male, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 164: 5)
- Transgression, 1996 (Box-folder 165: 6)
- Twitty, Conway, undated (Box-folder 165: 7)
  Original music sheet
- Unabomber, undated (Box-folder 165: 8)
- Underclass, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 165: 9)
  Clipping, magazines, and reports
- Urban decay, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 165: 10)
- Venture capitalism, 1997 (Box-folder 165: 11)
- Veterans, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 165: 12)
- University Club, Washington, D.C., 1994-1997 (Box-folder 165: 13)
  Membership directory and a quarterly issue
- Stallone, Sylvester, 1993 (Box-folder 165: 1)
- Stark, Steven, 1994 (Box-folder 165: 2)
- Steele, Shelby, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 165: 3)
  Article, clipping, and miscellany
- Stone, Roger, 1989 (Box-folder 165: 4)
  Article by Michael Callahan
- Success, 1997 (Box-folder 165: 5)
- Sulloway, Frank, 1996 (Box-folder 165: 6)
  Article by Robert S. Boynton
- Surgery, 1996 (Box-folder 165: 7)
- Switchers, 1989 (Box-folder 165: 8)
  Clippings, list of switchers by state, and magazine
- Tanner, Doug, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 165: 9)
  Article and memorandum
- Tax revolt, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 165: 10)
  Articles, clipping, note, press release, and report of post-election analyses of the statewide ballot proposition campaigns, 1984-1988
- Technology, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 165: 11)
- Terrorism, 1996 (Box-folder 165: 12)
  Press release
- Testing, 1973-1990 (Box-folder 165: 13)
  Article, clipping, journal, and report
- Testosterone, 1996 (Box-folder 165: 14)
  Clipping and materials relating to a workshop about parenthood
- Therapy, 1995 (Box-folder 165: 15)
- Kay Moseley edit (folder 2 of ?), 1999 (Box-folder 166: 1)
  Chapter 2
- Sports, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 166: 2)
- Rewrite September '98 (Box 167)
  - Folder 3 of 4, chapter 2 and new book introduction to "American Men"?, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 167: 1)
  - Folder 4 of 4, chapter 4, 1999 (Box-folder 167: 2)
- Kay Moseley edit (folder 1 of 2), 1998-1999 (Box-folder 167: 3)
  Correspondence, introduction, and outline
- Rewrite September '98 (Box 168)
  - Folder 2 of ?, editing of chapter 1 and summary, 1998 (Box-folder 168: 1)
  - Folder 3 of ?, chapter 1, 11/98 version, 1998 (Box-folder 168: 2)
- Paper and books to get, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 169: 1)
  Articles and book lists
- Entertainment, 2003 (Box-folder 169: 2)
- The pill, 2001 (Box-folder 169: 3)
- Outliers, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 169: 4)
  Articles, clippings, and magazine
- Men 2002 clips, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 169: 5)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, and magazine
- Sex differences, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 169: 6)
- List, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 169: 7)
  Clipping and magazines
- Infoneed (folders 1 and 2), 1998 (Box-folder 169: 8-9)
  Interviews, memoranda, and notes
- Human Behavior and Evolution Society (HBES), 1997-1998 (Box-folder 170: 1)
  Articles, correspondence, and program
- Rewrite September '98 (folder 1 of ?), 1998 (Box-folder 170: 2)
  New introduction
- High risk business (Box 171)
  - Folder 1 of 2, clippings, 2002 (Box-folder 171: 1)
  - Folder 2 of 2, articles and book, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 171: 2)
- Men on bottom
  - Bad men celebrities, 1994-2001 (Box-folder 171: 3)
    Articles, clippings, and press release
  - Male violence, 1993-2001 (Box-folder 171: 4)
    Articles, clippings, magazine, and press release
  - Male business failure, 1993-2001 (Box-folder 171: 5)
  - Motor vehicle crash data, 2001-2003
- 2004 clips (folder 1 of 3) (Box-folder 172: 1)
- Men--Proof of dominance (folder 2 of 2), 1996-1997 (Box-folder 172: 2)
  Directories
- 2004 clips (Box 173)
  - Folder 2 of 3, articles and magazines, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 173: 1)
  - Folder 3 of 3, books, 1990-1993? (Box-folder 173: 2)
- Men--Proof of dominance (folder 1 of 2), 1994-1998 (Box-folder 173: 3)
  Articles, chapter draft, and magazines
- Clips for TBE to read August 2000 II (Box 174)
  - Dominant men, 2000 (Box-folder 174: 1)
  - Data, 1996 (Box-folder 174: 2)
  - Feminists, 2000 (Box-folder 174: 3)
    Interview of Joyce Fletcher by John Koch
  - Testoterone, 2000 (Box-folder 174: 4)
    Text of a lecture by Harvey C. Mansfield
  - Magazines, 2000 (Box 174)
  - Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 174)
- Clips sorted by TBE 8/94 number 2 (Box-folder 175: 1)
  - Articles and magazines, 1978-1994 (Box 175)
  - Clippings, 1992-1994 (Box 175)
- Baby ceiling, 2003 (Box-folder 176: 1)
- Outlines, 2003 (Box-folder 176: 2)
  Memoranda and notes
- Resale amalgam (2003 August 19), 1999-2003 (Box-folder 176: 3)
  Drafts and chapter 1 amalgamated
- Resale amalgam (2003 August 19), 2000-2003 (Box-folder 176: 4)
  Notes and drafts
- Affirmative action, 2002 (Box-folder 176: 5)
- TBE September 2003 info clips, etc., 1994-2003 (Box-folder 176: 6)
  Articles, clippings, and interviews
- Military, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 176: 7)
- Afghanistan, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 176: 8)
- War and gender, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 176: 9)
- Moseley/Crittenden re. book, 2003 (Box-folder 176: 10)
- Material in this basket is info MDE wants to put in book during edit, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 177: 1)
- Unsorted clips, 1962-2001 (Box-folder 178: 1)
- Clips TBE using (2000 April 9) "American Men", 1997-2000 (Box-folder 179: 1)
  Articles, clippings, magazines, and memoranda
- Hypercomp (Hypercompetition) (Box 180)
  - Income--Articles and clippings, 1986-1998 (Box-folder 180: 1)
  - Articles, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 180: 2)
  - Magazines, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 181: 1)
  - Articles, 1984-1997 (Box-folder 181: 2)
  - Jobs--Articles and clippings, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 182: 1)
  - Clippings, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 182: 2)
- Materials used in book (2003), 1996-2004 (Box-folder 183: 1)
- 2003 August--Prints of what TBE writes daily AKA drafts, 2003 September 19 (Box-folder 183: 2)
  Drafts